Simon Sahli

IT Consultant / Project Manager

Ten years of experience in different areas of the IT sector. Demonstrated track record of successfully managing Software implementation project from start to finish with subsequent customer support as the key account manager. Focused on process optimisation for customers through improved software configuration, optimised data and by providing the necessary knowledge.



simon.sahli@hotmail.com

+41 79 304 97 56

Stockholm, Sweden 👂

22 November, 1989

simonsthlm.github.io./

linkedin.com/in/simon-sahli-88b0a0173 in

https://join.skype.com/invite/exqa1llyrdfz

GENERAL SKILLS

Application Management

Project Management (IPMA D)

Requirement Engineering (IREB)

Product Owner (PSPO)

Software evaluation

Finance Industry Background

Troubleshooting

Analytical Thinking

Scope and Interfaces

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Database SQL Statement, MS Access, Data

Migrations

Windows

MS Office (Excel advanced), Client, Server Environment (AD, DNS, SCCM,

Exchange)

Atlassian Jira (Project Administrator),

Confluence (Basics)

Linux

RedHat, Command-Line

Programming HTML / CSS, VBA, UML

Methodologies Agile, Waterfall, Scrum, UML, Git

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sabbatical

Travelling and Studying

02/2020 - Present

Sabbatical year with a stay in San Diego (CA) and travelling through Europe. Due to the Pandamie plans had to be changed multiple times. During the + 3 month of staying at home, I used the time to study subjects that were interesting to me.

Courses and Certifications done during the Sabbatical:

- Professional Scrum Product Owner I Certificat
- Project Administration in Jira Server Certificat
- Jira Essentials with Agile Course
- Confluence Content Management Course

Consultant

Profidata AG / Investment Management Software Manufacturer

0/2013 - 01/2020 Urdorf, Switzerland

Consultant for software implementation projects with customer management responsibility (Key account manager). Link between customers and development.

Tasks

- Managing and working on software implementation projects
- Performing data migrations (Excel and SQL)
- Consulting and implementation of technical and functional issues within and in the environment of the XENTIS software after extensive analyses
- Planning, coordination and implementation of software updates (Release management)
- Providing internal and external training
- Testing of new software modules

English Language courseWorkplace/Company

05/2013 - 09/2013

San Diego, USA

12 weeks intensive English course in Advanced level

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Support

Urner Kantonalbank

08/2010 - 04/2013 Altdorf, Switzerland

1st and 2nd Level ITSupport for the entire bank, In addition I was involved in smaller projects and I had some application responsibility.

Tasks

- Managing and solving IT support requests
- Single Point of Contact to Finnova, a banking ERP system
- Working and managing projects within the VoIP environment
- Visual Basic programming in the Office environment regarding banking use-cases

Database Project

RUAG AG

02/2010 - 07/2010 Emmen, Switzerland

Creating a MS Access Database from scratch within a seven weeks project. Temporary employment. During this time I also completed the Swiss compulsory military service as a tank driver.

IT Support

Amt für Informatik / Public IT Service Provider

09/2009 - 02/2010 Altdorf, Switzerland

First temporary job after completing my IT apprenticeship with the same company, which is an IT service provider in the public sector.

- 1st Level Support for all users in the organisation
- Installation and configuration from Windows Clients and Applications
- Maintenance within the Microsoft Server environment (AD, DNS, SCCM, Exchange)

LANGUAGES

English German French Swedish

Full Professional Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency Professional Working Currently Learning (SFI) Proficiency

CERTIFICATES

Jira Project Administration (06/2020)

Atlassian Certified

IPMA Level D (11/2019)

Certified Project Management Associate IPMA Level D

PSPO I (05/2020)

Professional Scrum Product Owner I

IREB Foundation Level (06/2019)

Certified Professional for Requirements Engineering

EDUCATION

Business Data Processing Specialist (Professional Bachelor)

Wirtschaftsinformatik Schule WISS (Business and IT school)

05/2015 - 05/2018 Bern. Switzerland

Course examples:

 Application-/ Information Engineering, IT Security, Business Administration, HR and Compliance

Information Technologist apprenticeship Federal vocational training

08/2005 - 07/2009

Altdorf, Switzerland

Course examples:

 Server-Client environment, Network configuration, Programming, Web (HTML) and databases

INTERESTS

Travelling Science and Technology Motorsport

Badminton



Basic banking training for adults BBZ (banking consulting centrum

Switzerland)

05/2010 - 10/2010

Altdorf, Switzerland

Course examples:

 Banking, settlement, trading (stocks, fonds), lending business